Guide to the Dimension Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials, Series VII; 6.8; (10 boxes)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes
    - Other subjects, 1969-1977, undated; (17 tapes) (Box 73)
      - Grass 2B-3A, Symposium '70, On Grass' Novel: "Local Anesthetic"; Ralph Freedman "The Poet's Dilemma: The Narrative Worlds", undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618849)
      - Grass 2B - 3A, Ernest Howard, 1st test, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618856)
      - Grass 3b, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618864)
      - Grass 3b, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618872)
      - Grass 3b, undated; 1 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002104618880)
    - Other subjects, 1969-1977, undated; (21 tapes) (Box 74)
      Contents include: Peter Handke, Kasper; Hitler speeches; Ernst Jandl; Günter Kunert (colloquium, 1972); Reinhard Lettau (address, 1969 April 9); Martin Walser (interview, 1973 October 9)
      - Jandl: Mona Lisa, Tape 33, duplicate, undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137181906)
      - A. Leslie Willson, Uwe Johnson: "Some Aspects of the Relationship Between German Literature + Politics", 1967 May 3; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137181914)
        Delivered in Austin, University Academic Center
      - Kempowski: Beethoven's Fünfte, Tape 27, undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137181922)
      - Jandl, "Spaltungen", Tape 26, 1981 February; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137181930)
      - "Christopher Middleton reading extracts from Karl Kraus: Die letzten Tage der Menschheit", undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137181948)
      - "Valerie Kreuzer - Interview with Leslie Willson, USK...", undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137181955)
      - Günter Kunert, Colloquium, 1972 December 6; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137181963)
      - "Ernst Jandl: Das Roecheln der Mona Lisa", Tape 25, undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137181971)
      - Walser interview, 1973 October 9; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137181989)
      - Lettau Address, 1969 April 9; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137181997)
      - Tape 20, "Jelka"..., undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode -39002137182003)
      - Tape 19, "Lleine Fähig keilen"..., undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182011)
      - Dimension #6, undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182029)
      - Ernst Jandl, BEB, Nov. 4, 1971, 3-4:45 p.m., 1979 July 2; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182037)
      - Hitler Speeches, undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182045)
      - Peter Handke: Kaspar (Teil 1), undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182052)
      - Peter Handke: Kaspar (Teil 2), undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182060)
      - Tape 37, Dimension, undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182078)
      - Tape 38, Dimension, undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182086)
      - Tape 39, undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182094)
      - Dimension Tape 40, undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182102)
        A note is included with this audiotape reel. It reads: Leslie - Sorry I missed you. Here are the two tapes. Thank you - I enjoyed them (yours, that is - Becker). Also here's the full text of Fichte/genct. For you, Richard
    - Unidentified, 1972, undated; (13 tapes) (Box 74)
      - GR 5-3 Drau Ben vor der tur, Tapes 1+2, Tape 32, undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182110)
      - GR 6-24 2, 1972 July 18; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137181898)
      - GR 5-29, undated; 1 (Box 47, Item barcode 39002137182128)
      - GR 6-18, Oct 9+11, Hans Jurgen Heinrichs "Samuel ish kan Gelichh", 1972 July 14; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182136)
      - GR 6-19, 1972 July 14; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182144)
      - GR 6-20, ? Gabo Altoteiei, 1972 July 14; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182151)
      - GR 6-21 1, Nov 25, Dec 2, Trauerfeierlichkeiten für, 1972 July 14; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182169)
      - GR 6-21 2, 1972 July 14; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182177)
      - GR 6-21 3, undated; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182185)
      - GR 6-23 1, 1972 July 18; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182193)
      - GR 6-23 2, 1972 July 18; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182201)
      - GR 6-22 1, Die Fabelhafte geträume von Taifren Willy - Hörschau - Dick Higgins, 1972 July 18; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182219)
      - GR 6-24 1, 1972 July 18; 1 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002137182227)
    - Unidentified, 1972, undated; (23 tapes) (Box 75)
      - Copy 2, dual track?, undated; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182268)
      - Xmas [?], undated; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182318)
      - Mickey + Her Dog, undated; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182359)
      - Tape 48, Fünf Mann Menschen, 1981 February; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182276)
      - GR 6-25, Wolf Vostell?, 1972 July 18; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182284)
      - GR 6-26, 1972 July 18; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182342)
      - GR 6-27, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182334)
      - GR 6-28, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182326)
      - GR 6-29, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182367)
        Uwe Herms: Der Mann mit den verhodeten Hirnlappen (Hoispiel-Lesung + Dramatisierung)
      - GR-30, undated; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182375)
        A note on the case reads: French!
      - GR-31, Vorschrift (?), 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182383)
      - GR 6-32, Dr. Williams #7, 2/18/70, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182391)
      - GR 6-33, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182409)
      - GR 6-34, Int Eng Bk II, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182417)
      - GR 6-35, Stewart, Tape 44, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182425)
      - GR 6-36 1, Taar, Tape 45, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182433)
      - GR 6-36 2, Tape 46, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182441)
      - GR 6-37, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182458)
      - GR 6-38 1, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182466)
      - GR 6-38 2, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182474)
      - GR 6-38 3, 1972 July 19; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182482)
      - GR 6-39, 1972 July 20; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182292)
      - GR 6-55, undated; 1 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002137182300)
  - Videocassettes
    - Wolf Bierman in Leipzig, 1989 January 12; YCGLMSS29_0001; 1; 01:02:31; NTSC (Box 75, Item barcode 39002102302164)
    - Jurek Becker, Kamera 1, 1990 May 25; YCGLMSS29_0002; 1; 02:10:48; NTSC (Box 75, Item barcode 39002102302172)
    - Jurek Becker, Kamera 1 and 2 Teil 2, 1990 May 25; YCGLMSS29_0003; 1; 00:40:41; NTSC (Box 75, Item barcode 39002102302180)
    - Jurek Becker, Kamera 2 Teil 1, 1990 May 25; YCGLMSS29_0004; 1; 02:10:23; NTSC (Box 75, Item barcode 39002102302198)
    - Hans Bender interview at University of Texas (David J. Ward), 1979 Fall; YCGLMSS29_0005; 1; 00:40:55 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002102302206)
    - Franz Kafka: Ein Bericht fur eine Akademie, Dramatisierung, undated; YCGLMSS29_0006; 1; 00:58:34 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002102302214)
    - Brecht: Fatzer, Stanford Workshop, production by Andrzeg Wirth, undated; YCGLMSS29_0007; 1; 02:09:11 (Box 75, Item barcode 39002102302222)
  - Cassette Tapes
    - Author readings
      Authors include: Ilse Aichinger, Hans Bender, Heinrich Böll, Günter Eich, Hans J. Fröhlich, Günter Grass, Rudolf Hagelstange, Peter Härtling, Herbert Heckmann, Günter Kunert
      - #1 Heinrich Boll, Entfernung ron der Truppe / Rudolf Hagelstange, Die Puppe inder Puppe, undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181724)
      - #2 Hans Bender, Mit dem Postschiff / Herbert Heckmann, Benjamin und seine Väter, undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181732)
      - #3 Günter Eich, Unterwasser / Peter Härtling, aus Janck, undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181740)
      - #4 Ilse Aichinger: Alltag, undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181757)
      - Günter Grass: Ausgefragt, Leckerburg, Danach / Raoul Hausmann, Kurt Schwitters: Gerhard Rühm, Franz Mon, E. Jandl, Phonetische Poesie, undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181765)
      - Heinrich Böll: über mich selbst, undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181773)
      - Günter Kunert, Günter Grass, undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181781)
      - Hans J. Fröhlich: Austin, 1980 September 30; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181799)
    - Gruppe 47 conferences, 1962-1966
      Contents:
      Berlin, 1962 (3 tapes): 1/1 & 1/2, 2/1 & 2/2, 3/1 & 3/2
      Sweden, 1964 (3 tapes): 1/1 & 1/2, 2/1 & 2/2, 3/1 & 3/2
      Princeton, 1966 (2 tapes): 1/1 & 1/2, 2/1 & 2/2, 3/1)
      - Berlin, 1/1+1/2, 1962; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181807)
      - Berlin, 2/1+2/2, 1962; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181815)
      - Berlin, 3/1+3/2, 1962; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181823)
      - Sweden, 1/1+1/2, 1964; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181831)
      - Sweden, 2/1+2/2, 1964; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181849)
      - Sweden, 3/1+3/2, 1964; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181856)
      - Princeton, 1/1+1/2, 1966; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181864)
      - Princeton, 2/1+2/2, 1966; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181872)
      - Princeton, 3/1, 1966; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002137181880)
    - Gruppe 47 conferences, 1967, 1990; (2 tapes) (Box 77)
      Pulvermühle, 1967 (1 tape): 1/1 & 1/2
      Prague, 1990 June (1 tape): report for WDR by Joseph Weishaupt; short statements by Havlik, Helga Novak, Ilse Aichinger, Walter Höllerer; the short discussion of Goethe at the end is a piece of a previous report
    - Hörspiele (radio plays), (15 tapes) (Box 77)
      Playwrights include: Alfred Andersch, Ingeborg Bachmann, Peter Bichsel, Heinrich Böll, Friedrich Dürrenmatt, Günter Eich, Karl Hans Frank, Günter Bruno Fuchs, Ludwig Harig, Wolfgang Hildesheimer, Fred von Hoerschelman, Franz Hohler, Ernst Jandl, Manfred Janker, Gerhard Köpf
    - Hörspiele (radio plays), (9 tapes) (Box 78)
      Playwrights include: Gerhard Köpf, Dieter Kühn, Siegfried Lenz, Friederike Mayröcker, Franz Mon, W. E. Richartz, Wolfdietrich Schnurre, Urs Widmer, Gabriele Wohmann, Wolf Wondratschek
    - Interviews, 1982-1990; (7 tapes) (Box 78)
      Interview subjects include: Jurek Becker, Wolf Biermann, Henrich Böll
    - Interviews, 1982-1990; (3 tapes) (Box 79)
      Interview subjects include: Günter Grass, Uwe Johnson, Hans Werner Richter
    - Unidentified, (8 tapes) (Box 79)
  - Long-Playing Records
    - Broch, Hermann. Die Entsühnung (Austrian Institute Education Recordings, ALS3), undated; (2 copies) (Box 80)
    - Jandl, Ernst. Ernst Jandl. him hanflang war das wort (Verlag Klaus Wagenbach, WA 20), c1980 (Box 80)
      Sleeve inscribed to A. Leslie Willson and Jeanne Willson, 1982 May 23
    - Mons, Franz, editor. Phonetische Poesie (Gema, F 60 379 B), undated (Box 80)
    - Wondratschek, Wolf; Brummbär, Bernd; Deuter, Georg. Maschine Nr. 9 (Philips, 6305 221), p1974 (Box 80)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21; (1 box)
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies are available for disks 4-6 and 8-11; reference copies for disks 1-3, 7, and 12-18 may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Original computer disks (Box 81)
- Oversize, 0.83; (4 boxes) + 1 broadside, 1 package, 1 roll
  - Subject Files (in Series I), Dimension Production Materials (in Series II), and Other Papers (in SeriesV) (Box 82)
  - Drawings and prints (in Series VI) (Box 83)
  - Drawings, prints, and posters (in Series VI) (Box 84)
  - Drawings, prints, and posters (in Series VI) (Box 85)
  - Drawings, prints, and posters (in Series VI) (Box 86 Broadside)
  - Posters (in Series VI) (Box 87 Package)
  - Posters (in Series VI) (Box 88 Roll)